本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
翻译  草血蛆   没网好心塞的时光蛆   红蛆公
翻译  大蛆粒酸奶   S蛆很爱笑   持久君   小shy
翻译  暴龙蛋   幸田实果子   Dust蛆   持久×小shy
校对   草血蛆   苏小黛   时间轴   薛定谔的蛆   三水
后期    鱼骨头      总监    蛆橙氏
血族  第一季  第六集
「血族」前情提要
Previously on The Strain...
你知道吗  我今天上地铁的时候
You know, I was getting on the subway today and I did see
看到十来只老鼠在站台上
like, ten rats. Like, on the platform.
老鼠一般不会这样
Rats don't migrate like that.
肯定是有什么东西把它们赶出来了
Something is driving them out of their nests.
比如说
Like what?
一种更强大的捕食者
A bigger predator.
该死
Oh shit.
天哪
Oh God!
我们说好了要找到治愈方法
We were talking about finding a cure.
可谁知道它的传染速度如此之快
That was before we knew how quickly it spreads.
这不是我的家
And this isn't my home.
我会陪你躺着  直到你睡着为止
I'll lie down with you until you fall asleep.
怎么回事
What's going on?
我们得走了  快点
We have to go, come on!
什么
What?
我们需要隔离所有与飞机上的死者有关的人
We need to lock down anyone related to the plane casualties.
我有实际证据表明死者正在回家
I have empirical proof that the victims are returning home
去感染他们的亲属
and infecting their families.
他们手上有录像
They have you on video
内容是你拖着雷德芬的尸体
dragging Redfern's body down the hallway.
我得走了
I have to get out of here.
扔掉电话  我来处理它
Drop your phone. I'll see what I can do.
...还有多起类似的大规模服务中断
Reporting similar accounts of widespread Service interruptions.
多个消息源称「自由公民」与此事有关...
Certain sources are implicating the "Citizens for liberty"--
美国国际市场继续大幅度下滑...
The us and international markets continue to plummet. The cure--
大家都很慌张  这简直...
Everyone's freaking out. I mean you've got, like,
就像新年前夜时代广场上那样
all the best elements of new year's eve and times square going on.
小偷小摸和变态都在活动
You got pickpockets and perverts doing their thing
再加上日食的事
and then you've got this added attraction of a lunar event.
不用说  大家都一惊一乍
And then of course, all those people are going like
「天哪  掩星是天启的预兆啊」
"Oh no! This occultation, that's the sign of some apocalyptic thing."
我也是这样的人
You guys, I am one Of those people.
我好害怕啊  现在城里的情况太乱了
I am freaking out, there's so much craziness in the city right now. -
就纽约这几天的新闻而言
The way the news is going in New York these days,
简直就像是世界末日
this could be the end of the world.
天哪
H-- oh my God...
不  不
No... No...
杀了我吧
Just k-- just kill me.
我就是要杀你
That is what I am doing.
不要啊
No! No!
求你了  别这样
Please! Please! Please! No!
不要啊
No!
谁救救我啊
Argh! Someone help me!
不要
N-- no!
不要啊
No! No! No!
救命啊  救救我
Please! Somebody help me!
我们等待世界改变的时候
But while we wait for the world to change,
我需要你再为我支撑几顿
I need you to last me a few meals more.
皇后区伍德赛德  凯尔顿街
凯莉·古德温泽  我是特别探员门罗
Kelly Goodweather? I'm special agent Monroe,
这位是特别探员伍德布里奇  我们是联调局的
this is special agent Woodbridge. FBI.
-好吧  -我们在找你丈夫
- Ok. - We're looking for your husband
伊弗雷姆·古德温泽博士  他在吗
Dr. Ephraim Goodweather. Is he here by any chance?
-不在  我们分居了  -真遗憾
- No. Um, we're separated. - Oh sorry to hear that.
我们找不到他
We've been having trouble reaching him.
你知道他现在在哪
Well, do you know where he is right now
或者我们怎么能联系到他吗
or how we can get in contact with him?
我有他电话号
I... I have his phone number.
不行  他的手机关了
No his cellphone has gone dark.
伊弗没事吧  这跟飞机的事有关吗
Wait, is Eph ok? Does this have something to do with the airplane?
是的
It does, yeah.
-怎么了  -联调局的  我是门罗探员
- What's going on? - FBI. I'm Agent Monroe
这位是伍德布里奇探员
and this is Agent Woodbridge.
我们在找伊弗雷姆·古德温泽  你是哪位
We're looking for Ephraim Goodweather. And you are?
马特·塞尔斯  凯莉的男朋友  怎么回事
Matt Sayles, Kelly's boyfriend. What's the matter?
这样吧  马特  我来处理
You know what, Matt, I've got it.
你去看看扎克
If you want to go check on Zack,
确保他没闲逛
make sure he doesn't wander over.
古德温泽博士要是联系了你们
If Dr. Goodweather gets in touch with either one of you,
麻烦立即告诉我们  我们将不胜感激
we'd appreciate it if you contacted us immediately.
没别的事的话  我得送儿子去上学了
If you don't mind, I have to get my son off to school.
你觉得他在里面吗
You think he's in there?
跟他老婆的男友共处一室  不可能
With his wife's boyfriend in the house? Eh, not a chance.
只能星期四  行吗
Can only be Thursday, can it?
布鲁克林  红钩区
你也忙成一团了吗
You jammed up too?
办公室的电话接连不断
Office's so flooded with calls,
我们都把生意推给竞争对手
we're referring business to the competition,
-他们也忙得四脚朝天  -我知道  笨蛋
- who're too busy to take it. - I know, you dope.
-我就是你们的对手  -肯定出事了
- I'm the competition. - Something's going on.
有哪个黑手党  抱歉  是卫生部
One of the mafia - 'scuse me, the Sanitation Department--
这周忘收垃圾了吗
forget to do their trash pick-up this week?
我昨天去莫特港一个楼顶上
I was on a roof in Mott Haven yesterday,
那里住了一堆老鼠  就跟一群鸽子似的
a whole squad of munchers livin' up there, like pigeons.
我在晨边高地见过他们从一个下水道口涌出
Yeah, I saw them pourin' out of a sewer in Morningside Heights.
有上百只  像「圣经」里的天灾似的
Hundreds. Like somethin' Biblical.
这是大规模迁居
It's a mass displacement.
有东西把他们从地下赶出来了
Something's driving them out from underground.
你怎么知道  费特
How you know this, Fet?
我见到他们了  在隧道里
I seen 'em. In the tunnels.
-见到什么了  -很大的东西
- Seen what? - Something big.
隐藏在地下的黑暗中
And it's hiding down there in the dark.
什么  鼹鼠人吗
What? The Mole People?
比起这些东西  你会更乐意遇见鼹鼠人
You'd be happy to see the Mole People instead of these things.
他们长什么样
What'd they look like?
我只是想说多加小心  仅此而已
I'm just saying be careful, that's all.
费特  下次你看见他们时
Hey, Fet. Next time you see 'em,
谢谢他们让我们加班
thank 'em for all the overtime.
哈莱姆  东第123街
-太无聊了  -来这可不是为了小打小闹
- Is this boring or what? - Didn't come here to pitty-pat.
漂亮小子  我向来不喜欢你
Pretty boy, I never liked you anyway.
这话可真让我伤心
Now you hurt my feelings.
来接人的吗
My ride here?
是的  我来找埃利萨尔德先生的
It is. I'm here for Mr. Elizalde.
这下不是小打小闹了吧
Pitty-pat that.
-谁找我  女王吗  -艾霍斯特先生
- With who? The queen? - Mr. Eichhorst.
不  我不再为他办事儿了
Nah, I don't work for him no more.
你还是请回吧  朋友
You'd better step up out of here, home boy.
恐怕他坚持如此
I'm afraid he insists.
好吧  兄弟  你悠着点
Alright, man. Be easy with that heat, eh?
我先去洗个澡  菲利克斯
Let me get cleaned up. Felix.
-什么事儿  -我之前替这个人办过事
- What's up? - This guy I used to work for.
现在还逼着我
Putting the press on me.
今天就把这事儿了结了
We gon' end that shit today, though.
他们想干什么
What did those men want?
-没事  -爸爸是不是有麻烦了
- Nothing. - Is dad in trouble?
-为什么这么问  -因为他上电视了
- Why do you ask? - 'Cause he's on TV.
疾控中心博士被通缉问话
联邦调查局要找他问话
Wanted for questioning by the FBI.
今早联调局宣布伊弗雷姆·古德温泽博士
This morning the bureau announced that Dr. Ephraim Goodweather
与失踪事件有关...
is a person of interest in the sudden disappearance of--
爸爸
Dad!
伊弗  你究竟做了什么
Eph what the hell did you do?
显然  昨晚雷德芬
Redfern apparently went missing last night
从圣塞巴斯蒂安医院失踪...
from St. Sebastian's hospital--
不管他们说什么
Whatever they're saying,
都是骗人的
it's completely bogus.
我们得马上把扎克送出城去
We need to get Zack out of the city right now.
去佛蒙特州找你妈妈吧
Go to your mother's in Vermont.
等等  你在说些什么啊
Wait-- what the hell are you talking about?
大事不妙了
Something awful is happening.
一种非常可怕的传染病暴发了
Um... The contagion. It's a terrible disease, an outbreak.
正在城里蔓延  而他们却想方设法
It's burning its way through the city and they're trying
让人们不相信我
to make sure nobody'll listen to me.
-那么糟啊  -你怎么进来的
- Is it that bad? - How did you get in here?
快去准备几件衣服  收拾下就出发吧
Just... Just pack a bag. Throw some clothes in, get out.
-你吓到我了  -我也被吓到了
- Look, you're scaring me. - I'm scared.
我从未见过这样的病  这是史无前例的
I've never seen anything like this. Nobody has.
如果事情这样紧急  为何没有一点风声呢
If there's some big emergency why isn't there any news about it?
为什么政府不警告我们  而是在到处找你呢
Why isn't the government warning us instead of looking for you.
他们想混淆视听
They're trying to turn it around on me.
我知道的太多了  也许这听起来很疯狂
Look, I know too much. Maybe that sounds crazy.
你得把手机扔了  不然他们会追踪到你的
You gotta get rid of your phone, dad. They can use it to trace you.
我已经这么做了
I did that already.
上楼去准备下  要去学校了
Go upstairs and get ready for school.
上楼去  扎克
Upstairs, Zack.
你吓到我了  也会吓到你儿子的
You're scaring me and you're going to scare your son.
是因为监护权听证会吗
Is it the custody hearing?
你是终于崩溃了吗
I mean, have you finally snapped?
你今早喝了多少酒  伊弗
How many drinks have you had this morning, Eph?
凯莉  你了解我的  你必须这么做
You know me Kelly. You need to do this.
你不能再给我下命令了
Look, you need to stop giving me orders, ok?
何况你说过多少次
Besides, how many times have you said
「人跑不过病毒」
"You can't outrun a virus"?
这次你至少得试试
Well this one, you need to try.
如果不是事关重要  我不会这么说的
Look, I wouldn't be saying this if it wasn't important!
你可以占用我的办公室  把它拆掉
You can take my office, you can tear it down,
你可以把它改造成游戏室  我无所谓
you can turn it into a game room, I don't give a shit.
但现在事关重大
But this matters.
-你居然打给联调局  -你这个傻逼
- You called the FBI? - Goddamn fool.
放轻松  博士  把你的手放在脑后
Take it easy, doctor. Put your hands behind your head.
好了博士  站着那别动
Ok, doc. Stop right there.
我的天哪  伊弗
My God, Eph.
我们只是要问你几个问题
We just have a few questions for you.
把手放在脑后
Put your hands behind your head!
快跑
Run.
他们让他坐在了后座
They left with him in the backseat.
我觉得邻居们应该没看到
I don't think any of the neighbours noticed anything.
你为什么要这么做
Why did you do that?
做什么  按照联调局的要求打给他们吗
What? Call the FBI as they instructed us to do?
怎么  你想让我们变成从犯吗
What? You want us to be an accessory to whatever?
这不是你可以决定的事
It wasn't your call to make.
-他强行闯入了我们家  -是我的家
- He forced his way into our house. - Into my house!
他是我前夫  我来决定怎么对待他
My ex-husband. And I will decide how to deal with him.
你居然在袒护他
You, you're actually defending him.
-为什么他们要抓走爸爸  -这只是
- Why did they arrest dad? - You know what? It was just
一个天大的误会  我们会解决的
a big misunderstanding and we're going to sort it out.
-我们要去佛蒙特州吗  -也许我们该去
- Are we going to Vermont? - You know what? Maybe we should.
-为了安全起见  -你说真的吗
- Just to be safe. - Are you kidding me?
然后呢  你就打算让扎克这么逃课了
And do what? You're just going to pull Zack out of school?
而且这么晚了你去找谁给你替课
And how are you going to find a substitute for your class this late?
抱歉  我可不要因为你前夫的胡扯丢了饭碗
I'm sorry, but I'm not losing my job because your ex went crazy.
不许这么说我爸爸
Don't say that about him!
扎克  到车里等我好吗
Zack, just go wait in the car for me, ok?
我知道你现在不开心  考虑到以前的事
Look, I know you're upset. With your history...
不  你闭上嘴听我说
No, you shut your mouth and you listen to me.
这是我的家庭  我的生活
This is my family, my life.
我让你参与其中
I invited you in,
你只是一个客人
you are a guest
-而你需要有个客人的样子  -客人
- and you need to start acting like one. - A guest?
也许这是个错误  也许我进展太快了
Maybe this was a mistake. Maybe I acted too quickly.
不不  我们的事我们心里有数  我在这
No no no. We know what we're doing here, ok? I'm here.
我在这是因为我爱你
I'm here because I love you.
我在这是因为我想保护这个家庭
I'm here because I'm trying to protect this family.
我早已不是客人了
We're way past me being a guest.
我得去上班了
I need to go to work.
-这事还没说完呢  -我说完了
- We're not done here! - I am.
行  行  我也得去工作了
Fine. Fine, I gotta go to work too.
-很好  -很好
- Great. - Great.
我们今晚要点库存  会有些晚
We've inventory tonight and it's gonna go late.
我不会等的
I won't wait up.
皇后区  奥松公园
我的剑闪耀着银色光辉
Sabia mea fredonaza argint.
布鲁克林  公园坡
妈妈  你还好吗  你还记得昨晚的事吗
Mama, are you OK? Do you remember anything from last night?
晚餐真不错
It-- it was a lovely dinner.
我真想像你一样忘掉
I wish I could forget like you.
你好
Hello?
诺拉  我是金  你还好吗
Nora, it's Jim. Are you alright?
不怎么好  伊弗联系你了吗
I've been better. Have you heard from Eph?
你不知道吗
You don't know?
他把雷德芬的尸检视频给了巴恩斯
He took Redfern's autopsy video to Barnes
结果他叫联调局来抓他
who put the FBI on him.
他被逮捕了
He has been arrested.
逮捕了
Arrested?
谁被逮捕了
Who's been arrested?
诺拉
So Nora...
他们看不清状况吗
Don't they see what's happening?
这说不通啊
This doesn't make any sense.
我知道
I konw...
诺拉  诺拉
Nora? Nora?!
金
Jim?
诺拉  你还在吗
Nora, are you there...
金  我听不到你了  别开
Jim, I'm losing you. Don't!
妈妈  别开门
Mama, don't open the door!
-诺拉  你又弄疼我了  -抱歉
- Nora! You're hurting me again. - I'm sorry.
-我很抱歉  -他们要让人消失吗
- I'm sorry. - Are they making people disappear?
我们得走了
We have to go.
别死在我车里
Don't die in my cab.
谢谢您的关心
Thank you for your concern.
哈莱姆挺远的  你钱够吗
Harlem is a long fare. You got money?
我钱够  就...
I have money. Just...
在日食前送我回家就行
Get me home before this eclipse.
嫌犯被捕  经过全市范围的搜捕
伊弗雷姆·古德温泽博士已被拘禁
这次日食要把大家逼疯了
This eclipse is making everyone nuts.
加上之前那个飞机的事  电话也用不了
The plane thing and cellphones aren't working.
整个城市都要疯了
The whole city's losing their minds,
就跟最终审判降临了似的
it's like judgement day out there.
你想扭转这一切吗
You wanna help fix this?
你想帮我阻止这一切吗
You wanna help me stop all of this?
你没法对付疯子的  老兄  没办法
You can't fix crazy, man. You can't.
曼哈顿  57街地下
-我们在哪啊老兄  -地狱上一层
- Where the hell are we, man? - One story above hell.
那人是恶魔的帮手  你带了我的枪吗
This idiot's the devil's butler. You got my gun on you?
带了
Yeah.
你还带了个朋友
Ah, you brought a friend.
听着  小白脸  我跟你说过我不干了
Look, slick. I told you. I'm out.
我怎样才能让你明白这一点呢
What do I gotta do to convince you that I'm done?
格斯  你违反了其中一条规则
Gus. You violated one of the three rules.
你想顺一点货走
You attempted to take some of the cargo.
因此我们的协议就失效了
The deal we made Therefore is no longer valid.
你还得听我差使
But you remain in my employ.
我没有看过箱子里的东西
I didn't look in that box.
我们不会争论这件事情了
We're not going to debate the issue.
这是你的新任务
Here is your new assignment:
在圣塞巴斯蒂安医院的地下室里
In the basement of St. Sebastian's hospital,
你会找到一具冷藏的尸体残骸
you will find the refrigerated remains of a body.
有个助手会带你找到这具尸体
An associate will pick you up and take you to this body.
你把它从医院里带出来
You will remove it from the hospital premises
然后再把它处理掉
and you will dispose of it.
我相信你自有安全的地方处理这种任务
I trust you know of a secure location for such a task.
我觉得你没懂我的意思
I don't think you're hearing me.
我们走
他要想拦我们  就干掉他
这个任务
酬劳是八百元
你的母亲也不会被驱逐出境
你懂了吗
你不该把她卷进来
You should never brought her into this.
你很爱她
You love her very much.
但我觉得有意思的是
What I find fascinating is
人们往往把爱说成一种馈赠  一种祝福
how love is considered a gift, a blessing,
却不肯正视爱其实是一种羁绊
with no acceptance to the fact that it also binds
枷锁  令人窒息
and chokes and strangles.
闭嘴  蠢货  你去死吧
Shut up, fool. You're over!
-怎么  -你到底是个什么东西
- Yes? - What are you?
我是你的救星还是噩梦  你自己选
I am your salvation or your downfall. Your choice.
你是个聪明人  格斯
You're a smart boy, Gus.
我想你不会再犯相同的错误
I doubt you will make the same mistake again.
现在  赶快去
Now get going!
国土安全部
联邦大厦
曼哈顿下城区  联邦广场26号
他们告诉你的一切都是捏造的
Everything you've been told is 100% false.
这么说你没杀多伊尔·雷德芬机长
So you didn't kill Doyle Redfern, the pilot?
是的  我没杀多伊尔·雷德芬机长
No. I did not kill Doyle Redfern the pilot.
你只是碰巧在走廊上拖着他的尸体
Just happened to be dragging his body down the hallway,
是这样吗
is that right?
你能给我儿子发条短信吗
Look, could you text my son?
你在他面前把我给拷走了
You handcuffed me right in front of him.
你只用打字就行  我口述
You can type it in, I'll dictate it to you,
我只是想让他知道我没事
he just needs to know that I'm ok.
但我不确定你是不是真没事  医生
Yeah, but I'm not sure that you are, Doc.
实际上  我更确信你大事不妙
In fact, I'm sure that you're not.
我不想再和你兜圈子了
Now I'm not going to dick around with you,
你现在是一堆麻烦缠身
you are in a shitstorm of trouble here
你能为自己做的最佳选择
and the best thing you can do for yourself
就是告诉我真相
is to tell me the truth.
听着  我知道这是你们办案的方式
Look, I know that this is the way that you do things
但我们真的没时间在这儿磨嘴皮子了
but we really just don't have time for this shit.
你现在有的只剩时间了  老兄
That's all you got is time, Fella.
不  我没有  我们都没有
No, I don't. We don't.
现在的时间很关键
These hours are crucial.
我们得利用日光进行战斗  捕杀它们
We need daylight to fight these things, to hunt them.
现在几点了
What time is it?
我才不管你是谁
I don't give a shit who you are
或是什么名牌医学院毕业的
or what fancy medical school you went to.
现在你落在我手上  让我出去
Now I own you. Buzz me out.
把这混蛋先在这儿关上一两天
Let's leave this asshole in here for a day or two
让他好好想想吧
and let him stew.
曼哈顿  西高速公路和58大街交叉口
是你
You?
-这是什么  -快穿上
- What's this? - Just put 'em on
别跟我说话
and don't talk to me.
给你钱  谢谢
Here you go, thanks.
曼哈顿  第28大街
-手机还是没信号  -我们这是要去哪儿
- Cellphone's still out. - Where are we going?
我不知道  妈妈
I don't know, mama.
但这里不安全  很快就要黑了...
But it isn't safe here. It'll be dark soon...
女儿啊  别犯傻了  现在可是大中午
Don't be silly mi hija, it's the middle of the day.
-日食眼镜  -在这等我
- Eclipse glasses! - Just wait here.
只要一块钱  卖纪念品啦
Just $1. Souvenirs!
日食眼镜
Eclipse glasses.
抱歉
Excuse me.
我想有人能帮我们
I think there's someone who can help us.
保护你的眼睛  只要一块
Protect your eyes! $1.
-我要坐下来  拜托了  -走吧  走吧
- Necesito sentarme, por favor! - Come on, come on.
-我们很快能到了  好吗  -好吧
- We'll be there soon, ok? - Ok.
皇后区  长岛市  28街
你们俩听说奥松公园房屋爆炸的事了吗
You two hear about the house explosion out in Ozone Park?
你居然还有个小女儿
Didn't know you had a little girl.
得来点更有力的家伙才行
Gonna need something with a little more punch.
偷吃贼溜进敌方总部了啊
Munchers sneaking in in the enemy headquarters, huh?
老大
Boss?
你还好吗
You alright?
好吧
Ok then.
劳蕾塔
Lauretta...?
你是对的
You were right.
应该多等几天
Shoulda waited a couple of days
不该现在就把他带过来
instead of bringing him back in.
还净听他这些瞎扯
And hearing this bullshit.
你们想听事情的全部  就这些了
You wanted to hear the whole story, that's it.
我已经告诉你们了  所有的事
I just gave it to you. All of it.
这就是真相
It's the truth.
这可不是全部  那家伙呢
Well, not everything. What about that guy?
彼得·毕什普  航空交通管制处主管
Peter Bishop. Head of airport ATC,
被发现死在肯尼迪机场
found dead at JFK.
他也是感染者之一吗
Was he also one of these infected people
也必须被消灭吗
who needed to be destroyed?
你们能不能稍微考虑下
How about just for one minute,
我有可能是对的
you entertain the possibility that I'm right.
现在正有一种严重的传染病
That there is a massive contagious event
在纽约城肆虐蔓延
rolling through New York city.
好啊
Ok.
你们就去某个乘客的家中
Well, just go to one of the passenger's houses.
随便选一个  看看会有什么发现
Just pick one, any one and see what you find there.
还是把这家伙关回监狱吧
Let's put this guy back in his cell.
再见了博士  我们五到六个月后法庭上见
Goodbye doctor, we'll see you in court in five or six months.
好吧  好吧  我...
Alright, alright, alright. I...
我带你们去找尸体  我知道尸体都在哪儿
I'll take you to the bodies. I know where the bodies are.
你现在是要换个说法了吗
Are you saying something different now?
-是的  -你知道尸体在哪吗
- I am. - You know where the bodies are?
-我知道  所有的  -把地址给我们
- I do. All of them. - Give us an address.
不不不  地址不行  我得带你们去看
No, no, no. No address. I need to show you.
我看他还是在扯蛋
It's just more bullshit.
不  不  我想做辩诉交易
No, no, no. I want to make a deal.
你要是敢耍我们
If you're jacking us around,
我会让你吃不了兜着走
what I did to you before was nothing.
你要是想弄清整件事
You want answers to your questions
一直待在这里可不行
you're not going to find them in here.
就我所知  日食是法语欢乐时光的意思
As far as I'm concerned, eclipse is French for happy hour.
我从来没见过伊弗这样
I've just never seen Eph like that.
他就是故意给你们添堵
It's a classic cock-block.
现在城里危机四伏  一触即发
Oh, there's just some big city wide emergency,
快救你和儿子  我是你们的大英雄
save yourself and Zack, I'm your hero.
我是说  我狠狠地呵斥了马特
I mean, I just shut Matt down hard.
他只是想帮忙
He was trying to help.
虽然是帮倒忙  但有这份心
Failing, but trying.
其实你也没做错
Hey, what you did was fine.
有些事情有时候需要慢慢来
They need to be put in their place from time to time.
他到现在都没联系我
He hasn't called or texted,
这一点都不像他
I mean, that is so not like him.
男人都爱面子
That's male pride.
你觉得这里的装修
You think this redecorating thing
是他的心血来潮吗
is some random home improvement?
他没搞大男子主义宣布主权
You're lucky he's not marking his territory
你就偷着乐吧
in a more traditional way.
也许不该那么快让他搬进来
Maybe I let him move in too soon.
也许我就是想气气伊弗
Maybe I did want to hurt Eph.
离婚就像是街头斗殴
Hey. Divorce is a street fight.
你可别忘了伊弗那份奇葩工作
Don't you forget about Eph's spicy
让你遭的罪  好吗
side-dish there at work, Ok?
-不要动摇  -也对
- Stay strong. - Right.
要是被伊弗说对了怎么办
And what if Eph's right?
不知道...
I don't know...
那就去佛蒙特州
Then go to Vermont.
你要是觉得有压力  就给自己放个长假
Take a long weekend if you're stressing out about it.
你不用去解释  也不用...
You don't have to justify it, you don't have to...
也不用征求马特的同意
you don't have to ask Matt's permission.
-去吧  你应得的  -好  那你呢
- You go, you deserve it. - Right. What about you?
你就不担心真的有疫情暴发
You're not worried that there's some horrible new epidemic
而政府却对我们有所隐瞒吗
they're not telling us about?
你想跟我们一起走吗
You want to come with us?
当然不  小凯  拜托
Nah. Kel, come on.
生是皇后人  死做皇后鬼
I'm a Queens girl, we never leave.
皇后区  长岛市  韦尔南大街
天  感觉这里面又粘稠又恶心
Man, it's so loose and nasty in there.
我跟你说  肯定被人分尸了
I'm telling you, someone got their ass chopped up.
是谁啊  黑帮的人还是政客
Who is it? Mob guy? Politician?
你不用知道那么多
You don't need to know.
别多管闲事  菲利克斯
Leave it alone, Felix.
想得美  兄弟  我得瞧瞧
Nice try, Homie. I gotta see this.
别  别打开  你疯了吗
Hey! Stop! Stop! Stop! Hey, what are you doing?!
这货不是人类啊
That shit ain't human.
还不滚开
Get out of the way!
该死
Goddamnit.
我们赶紧了事吧
Let's get this over with.
布鲁克林  布莱顿海滩  布莱顿一街
-爸爸  -瓦西里
- Pop. - Vasiliy.
-妈不在家吗  -她就回来
- Mom's not home? - She's on her way.
去集市了
Market day.
烤肉饼
Pirozkhi.
熟悉的味道  刚做的吗
Always. Fresh made, huh?
你要钱吗
You need money?
抱歉让你失望了
Sorry to disappoint you.
还搞「疯狂天才」的那一套啊
Still the Mad Genius I see, huh?
快完成了
It is almost done.
「乌克兰建筑史」
The History of Ukrainian Architecture.
作者却是三十年前就离开那里
Authored by a man who fled the country 30 years ago
-再没回去的人  -我的书即于六月份
- to never return. - My book is to be published
由敖德萨国立大学大学出版社出版
in June by the Odessa Mechnikov University Press.
我还受邀秋天去敖德萨讲座
I have also been invited to lecture there in Odessa,
-还有哈科夫和基辅市  -恭喜你啊
- Kharkiv and kiev in the fall. - Congratulations.
你呢瓦西里
And you Vasiliy?
忙着杀老鼠  都没时间来看妈妈吗
Too busy killing rats to come visit your mother?
我还一直想你能不能放下这事
I always wonder if you'll get past it.
约德嘉夫妇还以为我是市规划局的吗
Do Mr. and Mrs. Yodka still think I work in City Planning?
我要为你的工作到处宣扬吗
I should advertise what you do?
如果我告诉别人你拒绝了
Is there any gain for me in telling people
康乃尔大学的建筑学研究生奖学金
that you turned down a graduate school scholarship
去做捕鼠员  对我有什么好处
in Architecture at Cornell to become a rat catcher?
是没什么好处
No. Not much.
但我不是来跟你吵的
But I didn't come here to fight.
我是来警告你的  你和妈妈
I came here to warn you. You and Ma.
你们得马上离城
You need to get out of this city.
为什么
And why is that?
邪恶在这里扎根了
Something evil has taken root.
一种疾病  异常可怕的菌株
Some disease. Some horrible, horrible strain.
城里在暴发瘟疫
A pestilence that's overrunning the city.
把人变成了饥渴的害虫
It's turning people into hungry vermin.
瓦西里  你的工作  扭曲了你的理智
Your job, Vasiliy, it has warped your mind--
这是实话
It's the truth.
这是我的工作  我了解这个
This is what I do. This is what I know.
你得跟妈妈去度假  你早就答应过她
You need to take that vacation you always promised ma,
却一直没实现  你们得走
but never given her. You know, you need to go.
我就知道会这样
I knew this would happen.
你走了两年  现在突然出现
You appear after two years.
要我背井离乡  凭什么
And I'm supposed to flee my home on what?
陌生人的只言片语吗
The word of a stranger.
我劝过你了
I tried.
再见  爸爸
Goodbye, da.
留下来  为了你妈
Stay. For your mother.
快走
Go.
为了我
For me.
谢谢
Thanks.
一定要戴好了再抬头看啊
Make sure you put these on before you look up.
好神奇
It's so cool.
我不喜欢日食
Yeah, I don't like it.
这是不祥之兆
It's a bad omen.
我们怎么做  小扎  留下还是离开
So what should we do, Z? Stay here or go?
爸爸说离开
Dad says go.
很抱歉今早让你看到那些
I'm sorry you had to see that this morning.
很抱歉现在所有事情都一团糟
I'm sorry everything is so chaotic right now.
可能我们都需要点正常的状态  是吧
Maybe what we both need is a little normalcy, huh?
没有哪里能比得上自己家
No place like home, right?
而且你还要上学
And you've got school.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you, too.
曼哈顿  中城区  第46街
快走啊
C'mon.
为什么走这条路
Why'd we go this way?
因为我手机上是这么显示的
Because my phone told me to.
老天啊  快看
Jesus, look at that!
班尼特
Bennett?
什么
What?
那是曼哈顿的验尸官
That's the Manhattan medical examiner.
就是他  之前这个人
That's the guy right there who disappeared
和乘客的尸体一起消失了
along with the bodies of the passengers.
就是他  就是那个人
That's him, right there.
他只是个无家可归的疯子
He's just a crazy homeless guy.
上帝啊
My God!
他妈的
Holy shit!
别管他  这不归我们管
Leave it, it's not our problem.
-你开什么玩笑  -别管他
- You kidding me? - Leave it!
-万恶的纽约  -别  别去
- Damn New York City... - No. No! No! No!
等等  站住  探员  别去
Wait! Wait! Stop! Federal agent! Stop!
住手  我说了住手
Stop! I said stop!
联调局  不许动
FBI. Freeze!
救我  求你
Help... Please...
钥匙给我  钥匙给我
Give me your keys. Give me your keys!
救我
Help me.
我警告过你的
I warned you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
皇后区  雷格公园中心
哥们儿  你错过天上的好戏了
Yo matty, you missing the big show in the sky.
你没事吧
You ok, man?
没事  我跟女朋友吵架了
Yeah, yeah, I... just got into a fight with my girlfriend.
想找个法子跟她和好
Just trying to find a way to make it right.
别发短信  一点诚意都没有
Ah, don't text her man. It's impermanent.
不过我倒是认识个人
Look I know a guy who could
能帮你想出非常诚恳的道歉方案
sleeve you up a real apology, though.
我还是想着送送花什么的  不过谢了
I was thinking more along the lines of flowers, but thanks.
好吧
Alright.
杰夫  出什么事了
Jeff, what happened?!
快叫保安  拿急救箱  快去
Call security, get a first aid kit. Go! Go!
没事的  救护马上就来了
Everything-- help is on the way, ok buddy?
谁  是谁干的  是谁干的
Who...who did this? Who did this?
多起报告称有可怕的攻击事件...
Many reports of gruesome attacks occurring...
是不是你们干的
Did you do this?!
那袋子里是什么  哥们儿
What was in the bag, homie?
别吵  让我想想
Shut up, bro. Let me think.
格斯图  咱们该把它烧了  还得找个神父
We should've burned it Gusto. Need a priest.
我该用圣水好好洗一下手
Coulda washed my hands in holy water.
我说多少次了  别管了  菲利克斯
How many times I gotta tell you...let it go, Felix.
接我们那哥们儿
That dude who picked us up...
他吓坏了  你也是
He was scared, and so were you.
还有那德国佬  我们今天碰到了魔鬼
And that German dude? We met a diablo today, esse...
我跟你说过了  闭嘴
Man, I told you. Shut up!
我没有害怕  怕的是你
I wasn't scared, you were scared.
别激动伙计  放松
Hey yo, be easy man. Relax.
退后  伙计  退后  他妈的
Back up, man. Back up, puto.
格斯图  救我  救我
Gusto! Help! Help!
这什么啊  格斯图  救我
What is it? Gusto, help!
-什么玩意儿  -把它拽出来
- What is it? - Get it off!
这他妈什么玩意儿  把它拽出来
What is that shit, bro? Get it out!
警察
Hey! Police!
过来
Come here!
-好了  不准反抗  -现在才知道露面吗
- Here we go. Stop resisting! - Ha! Ha! Ha! Now you show up.
哈莱姆  东118街
我准备好谈谈了
I'm ready to talk.
跟我来
Follow me.
你来了
You're here.
你们都准备好了  很好
You're both ready. Good.
我有个新计划
I have a new plan.